# **Martin Klefas-Stennett**

Phone: 07985 706256 | Email: martin.klefas@hotmail.com

GitHub: https://martinklefas.github.io/ | https://www.linkedin.com/in/martin-klefas-stennett/

# Skills Machine Learning Python Computer Vision C++ Fortran90 Srategic Thinking Problem Solving

### **Education**

Relationship Building

- 2023 AiCore Machine Learning Bootcamp
- 2006-2008 Ph.D. Computational Chemistry,U. of Manchester (Published, not completed)
- **2005-2006** M.Sc. Computational Science & Engineering, U. of Manchester (Merit)
- **2002-2005** B.Eng. Chemical Engineering, UMIST (2:2)

# Languages

Basic Polish, French & German

### **Hobbies**

Photography enthusiast, World Travels, Triathlon

### **Personal Profile**

After more than 13 years of experience in sales and business development, creating and using automation and analysis tools to enhance productivity, I retrained in machine learning. I am eager to apply my new skills to a career in machine learning, combining my background in account management, automation & analytics, relationship building, and strategy with a passion for cutting-edge technology.

## **Career History**

### **Business Development Roles:**

Insight UK Ltd - Public Sector Business Development Manager (2014 - Present)

I streamlined the role by automating labor-intensive repetitive tasks using VB.net, MSSQL and SQLLite, which allowed me to focus on delivering greater value to the business. As a result, I successfully:

- Secured and developed relationships with vendors specific to the Insight UK Public Sector business, focusing on HP, Cisco, and Dell as key suppliers.
- Guided the campaign and sales activities of partners and managers by providing and amending sales data reports to suit their needs.
- Worked on major Public Sector opportunities, engaging with C-Level contacts and securing multi-million pound tender wins for Insight.
- Developed and implemented automated workflows for various areas of the business, streamlining processes and improving overall efficiency on an informal basis.

### **Direct Sales Roles:**

### Insight UK Ltd - Internal Account Manager (Education) (2013 - 2014)

- Designed simple automation steps to maximise productivity
- Responsible for recommending appropriate options to meet challenges faced by Network Managers & senior staff.
- Analysed sales & marketing data to allow me to exceeded all targets for gross profit.

### ANSYS UK Ltd. - Academic Account Manager (2009 - 2012)

- Sold engineering simulation software suite directly into the UK academic market.
- Understood strategic goals of departments and universities to position sales.

### **Other Sales Roles:**

### NCC Group Ltd. (2012) & Egencia - Internal Account Manager (2012)

- · Generated new business leads for an external account manager.
- Exceeded all targets for growth and meeting bookings.

### ANSYS UK Ltd. - Internal Sales Rep. (Team leader) (2008 - 2009)

- Promoted the value of ANSYS Software and consultancy services
- Generated leads for a sales team of 12-14 external account managers.
- Automated essential marketing tasks, leading to increased reach and reduced marketing expenditure while optimizing campaign performance.